[
    { "question": "", "answer": "" },
    {
        "question": "Most people want to do good work that makes them feel _____.",
        "answer": "productive"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most recent _____ has caused a lot of problems for the world’s economies.",
        "answer": "pandemic"
    },
    {
        "question": "The book provided a very basic plan for _____ organizations to help save the logical environment.",
        "answer": "grassroots"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action happened last?I could see from my sister's expression that she had been arguing with her husband.",
        "answer": "I could see"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action came last?I had already finished the report when my study partners asked what they could do to help.",
        "answer": "my study partners asked what they could do to help"
    },
    {
        "question": "fortunately ... often ... frequently ... usually",
        "answer": "fortunately"
    },
    {
        "question": "They say the extreme weather conditions ___ by the middle of the century.",
        "answer": "will have worsened"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditional form does the sentence use?If the temperature drops to 0°, water freezes.",
        "answer": "zero conditional"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditional form does the sentence use?Plants die if you don’t water them.",
        "answer": "zero conditional"
    },
    {
        "question": "I think working overseas would be a wonderful _____ for you.",
        "answer": "experience"
    },
    {
        "question": "I haven’t been sleeping well, and this seems to caused an _____ of pimples on my face.",
        "answer": "outbreak"
    },
    {
        "question": "I’m sorry to say that there has been another _____ of Covid 19 this month.",
        "answer": "outbreak"
    },
    {
        "question": "I tied my shoes very tightly, and now I can't _____ the knot!",
        "answer": "undo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action happened first?So much rain had fallen that the students were unable to drive to school.",
        "answer": "So much rain had fallen"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action happened last?She got to work late because she had missed her bus.",
        "answer": "She got to work late"
    },
    {
        "question": "my / boyfriend / that / last / forgot / week / birthday / my / nearly / believe / can't / I",
        "answer": "I can't believe that my boyfriend nearly forgot my birthday last week."
    },
    {
        "question": "They will be in a meeting ___.",
        "answer": "between 2:00 p.m. and 3:00 p.m."
    },
    {
        "question": "___, she will be driving home from work.",
        "answer": "At 6:30 p.m. tomorrow"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditional form does the sentence use?If she wants to be in shape, she has to exercise regularly.",
        "answer": "zero conditional"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditional form does the sentence use?I’ll call you after I get home.",
        "answer": "first conditional"
    },
    {
        "question": "Getting a high score on the university entrance exam was quite a _____ for her, but she did well.",
        "answer": "difficulty"
    },
    {
        "question": "I can’t wait to _____ the Northern Lights in Iceland. If you come with me, it would be perfect!",
        "answer": "experience"
    },
    {
        "question": "Creating a new way to fight certain types of cancer was the doctor’s best-known _____.",
        "answer": "achievement"
    },
    {
        "question": "Many people think a world war would cause an _____ for life on Earth.",
        "answer": "apocalypse"
    },
    {
        "question": "City traffic is a large cause of _____ pollution.",
        "answer": "carbon"
    },
    {
        "question": "Covid-19 was _____ for the loss of tourism in the beach resort.",
        "answer": "to blame"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action came last?Sally had only been to the ocean once before, so she was nervous about swimming at the beach.",
        "answer": "she was nervous about swimming at the beach"
    },
    {
        "question": "fortunately ... seldom ... rarely ... usually",
        "answer": "fortunately"
    },
    {
        "question": "actually ... under ... behind ... somewhere",
        "answer": "actually"
    },
    {
        "question": "our / it / class / Monday / make / meeting / to / I / unfortunately / cannot / next",
        "answer": "Unfortunately, I cannot make it to our class meeting next Monday."
    },
    {
        "question": "We’ll be having that big meeting ___. You had better be prepared!",
        "answer": "in a few days"
    },
    {
        "question": "You can borrow my car tomorrow. I ___ it then.",
        "answer": "won’t be using"
    },
    {
        "question": "My father will call me after he ___ at his hotel.",
        "answer": "checks in"
    },
    {
        "question": "They ___ their homework by the time their parents come back.",
        "answer": "will have finished"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditional form does the sentence use?I will visit you as soon as I arrive.",
        "answer": "first conditional"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you want to _____ your weight, think about exercising more instead of eating less.",
        "answer": "reduce"
    },
    {
        "question": "The best thing that a teacher can do is to make sure that his or her students leave school with _____ knowledge in their chosen fields.",
        "answer": "informed"
    },
    {
        "question": "My mother sold all of her stocks as soon as the stock market started to _____.",
        "answer": "decline"
    },
    {
        "question": "I put my finger right through the paper — I didn’t realize how _____ it was.",
        "answer": "delicate"
    },
    {
        "question": "It’s very difficult to _____ bad grammar habits without a lot of practice.",
        "answer": "undo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action came last?My father yelled at me because I had crashed his brand new red Italian sports car.",
        "answer": "My father yelled at me"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action happened last?We had been sitting in class for 15 minutes when the teacher came in.",
        "answer": "the teacher came in"
    },
    {
        "question": "certainly ... apparently ... occasionally ... honestly",
        "answer": "occasionally"
    },
    {
        "question": "By this time tomorrow, we ___ over the Pacific Ocean to Canada.",
        "answer": "will be flying"
    },
    {
        "question": "Don’t call her between one and two o’clock. She ___ lunch during that time.",
        "answer": "will be having"
    },
    {
        "question": "It looks like we ___ different weather patterns in the future.",
        "answer": "will be having"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will get some gas now ___ the price goes up later.",
        "answer": "in case"
    },
    {
        "question": "As soon as they ___ the English exam, they will go to America.",
        "answer": "pass"
    },
    {
        "question": "The politician had some problems after she accepted a large _____ from a well-known criminal.",
        "answer": "contribution"
    },
    {
        "question": "We need to have stronger laws to limit the _____ of polluting gases, such as carbon dioxide.",
        "answer": "emission"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forest was recently named a firefly _____ area, so you can’t go in without permission.",
        "answer": "conservation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whenever there is a period of bad events, people often call it an _____.",
        "answer": "apocalypse"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action happened first?I didn't recognize Maria at the party because she had changed a lot since I last saw her.",
        "answer": "she had changed a lot"
    },
    {
        "question": "enough ... fully ... yesterday ... very",
        "answer": "yesterday"
    },
    {
        "question": "near ... there ... quickly ... downstairs",
        "answer": "quickly"
    },
    {
        "question": "hourly ... still ... increasingly ... rarely",
        "answer": "increasingly"
    },
    {
        "question": "had / we / movie / ever / that / the / was / worst / absolutely / that / seen",
        "answer": "That was absolutely the worst movie that we had ever seen."
    },
    {
        "question": "We will have finished all our tests ___.",
        "answer": "by Friday"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hopefully, you will have recovered ___ I see you.",
        "answer": "by the next time"
    },
    {
        "question": "You ___ if you don’t wear a mask in public.",
        "answer": "can be fined"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sophie will buy some souvenirs before she ___ Japan.",
        "answer": "leaves"
    },
    {
        "question": "This country’s _____ has been improving as a result of global trade.",
        "answer": "economy"
    },
    {
        "question": "The need to protect our environment is quickly entering the _____ of the public.",
        "answer": "consciousness"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action happened first?Kathy had a bandage on her leg because she had fallen off her scooter yesterday.",
        "answer": "Kathy had a bandage on her leg"
    },
    {
        "question": "really / difficult / would / thought / quite / it / easy / was / be / we / class / actually / the / but",
        "answer": "We thought the class would be really easy but actually it was quite difficult."
    },
    {
        "question": "___, she will have written five reports.",
        "answer": "By the end of May"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you don’t hurry, ___we get to the stop, the bus will have left.",
        "answer": "by the time"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nancy ___ better as soon as she has a cup of black tea.",
        "answer": "will feel"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you could _____ some time to help us with our final project, we would really appreciate it.",
        "answer": "donate"
    },
    {
        "question": "actually ... frankly ... elsewhere ... sadly",
        "answer": "elsewhere"
    },
    {
        "question": "managing / her / time / good / amazingly / she's / at",
        "answer": "She's amazingly good at managing her time."
    },
    {
        "question": "good / was / school / high / have / I / lucky / extremely / math / to / teacher / in / had / a",
        "answer": "I was extremely lucky to have had a good math teacher in high school."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where ___ this holiday weekend?",
        "answer": "will you be going"
    },
    {
        "question": "The dog ___ his food until it sees its owner.",
        "answer": "won’t eat"
    },
    {
        "question": "She ___ a movie with us if she gets paid this afternoon.",
        "answer": "will go to"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you want to improve your test scores, you should try to _____ your diet. Good nutrition really helps you remember better.",
        "answer": "improve"
    },
    { "question": "almost ... barely ... ugly ... lots", "answer": "ugly" },
    {
        "question": "I probably ___ the assignment by this coming Friday.",
        "answer": "won’t have finished"
    },
    {
        "question": "In case I ___ what to buy, I will make a shopping list.",
        "answer": "forget"
    },
    {
        "question": "Countries need to work hard to improve _____ in their poorest areas. Everyone has a right to live in a clean place.",
        "answer": "sanitation"
    },
    {
        "question": "A lot of people like to _____ in order to help their communities.",
        "answer": "volunteer"
    },
    {
        "question": "Over the last ten years, the _____ of students who leave Taiwan to study for Master’s degrees has been increasing.",
        "answer": "percentage"
    },
    {
        "question": "My classmates and I are going to Thailand to _____ to teach Chinese this winter.",
        "answer": "volunteer"
    },
    {
        "question": "It’s a _____ fact that not getting enough sleep affects your memory.",
        "answer": "well-known"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action happened first?My brother went to the police station and reported that someone had stolen his motorcycle.",
        "answer": "someone had stolen his motorcycle"
    },
    {
        "question": "not / difficult / at / would / but / be / the / that / it / so / looked / I / text / known / I / had / carefully",
        "answer": "I looked at the text carefully, but I had not known that it would be so difficult."
    },
    {
        "question": "because / like / really / argue / roommates / I / my / ever / we / anything / hardly / abou",
        "answer": "I really like my new roommates because we hardly ever argue about anything."
    },
    {
        "question": "He will have learned enough Japanese to go to Japan ___.",
        "answer": "in a few months"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ken ___ for Japan by next Saturday.",
        "answer": "will have already left"
    },
    {
        "question": "Some people think islands like Penghu will have disappeared ___.",
        "answer": "in eighty years"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditional form does the sentence use?My sister will stay at a friend’s house if she finishes work late.",
        "answer": "first conditional"
    },
    {
        "question": "If she gets eight hours of sleep, she usually ___ alert.",
        "answer": "feels"
    },
    {
        "question": "After studying a little bit of English each day, I really noticed that my speaking ability started to _____.",
        "answer": "improve"
    },
    {
        "question": "Scientists often _____ the effects of climate change in their reports.",
        "answer": "note"
    },
    {
        "question": "always ... never ... yesterday ... daily ... far",
        "answer": "far"
    },
    {
        "question": "She ___ enough money until at least early next year.",
        "answer": "won’t have saved"
    },
    {
        "question": "If we are lucky, we ___ to see the northern lights tonight.",
        "answer": "will be able"
    },
    {
        "question": "If Joe ___ the book, I will lend it to him.",
        "answer": "hasn’t read"
    },
    {
        "question": "You can really help the people of the village if you donate some money to that _____.",
        "answer": "charity"
    },
    {
        "question": "Will they be coming with us to see a movie ___?",
        "answer": "tonight"
    },
    {
        "question": "Susan made the largest _____ to the group project by working so hard to make sure that everything was correct in the report.",
        "answer": "contribution"
    },
    {
        "question": "Be careful with those butterfly wings — they’re very _____.",
        "answer": "delicate"
    },
    {
        "question": "My mother won’t give me any pocket money unless I ___ my room weekly.",
        "answer": "clean"
    },
    {
        "question": "I want to volunteer to help a local _____ this summer. I hope I can do some good for the people of my community.",
        "answer": "charity"
    },
    {
        "question": "I really studied hard this semester, and it resulted in a _____ improvement in my final grade for the class.",
        "answer": "notable"
    },
    {
        "question": "Taiwan’s birth rate has been on the _____ for several years now.",
        "answer": "decline"
    },
    { "question": "Please _____ my new telephone number.", "answer": "note" },
    {
        "question": "The professor was _____ for her ability to make difficult subjects easy to understand.",
        "answer": "well-known"
    },
    {
        "question": "When there are too many people who can't get jobs, the whole _____ suffers.",
        "answer": "economy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Since coming to college, I’ve noticed that I’ve _____ been gaining weight.",
        "answer": "steadily"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rats are an _____ species which did not live in Australia before people moved there.",
        "answer": "invasive"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a year, they ___ the high speed railway.",
        "answer": "will have built"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sixteen kilometers is _____ the same as ten miles.",
        "answer": "roughly"
    },
    {
        "question": "The president is very popular among his _____ supporters.",
        "answer": "grassroots"
    },
    {
        "question": "Many people consider kindness to one another to be the highest _____ of humanity.",
        "answer": "ideal"
    },
    {
        "question": "When you _____ something, you try to explain what it means.",
        "answer": "define"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the most _____ industries of Taiwan is its computer chip manufacturing.",
        "answer": "notable"
    },
    {
        "question": "I can’t believe my father is in the forest _____ his own Christmas tree this year.",
        "answer": "harvesting"
    },
    {
        "question": "We need to lower the _____ of gasses such as carbon dioxide if we want to slow down climate change.",
        "answer": "emission"
    },
    {
        "question": "The _____ of our water resources is extremely important for our economy.",
        "answer": "conservation"
    },
    {
        "question": "What _____ of your salary do you save each month?",
        "answer": "percentage"
    },
    {
        "question": "I don’t want to _____ the already bad situation with my girlfriend by telling her that I accidentally kissed her twin sister!",
        "answer": "worsen"
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the different animals on Earth are important, so we need to ____ them — even the ugly ones!",
        "answer": "protect"
    },
    {
        "question": "I’m sorry teacher, but I don’t quite know what this word means. Could you _____ it for me?",
        "answer": "define"
    },
    {
        "question": "There is no way I am _____ for your break-up with your girlfriend. I only talked to her once!",
        "answer": "to blame"
    },
    {
        "question": "The _____ effects of the new airport need to be studied before it can be built.",
        "answer": "ecological"
    },
    {
        "question": "She wants me to be perfect in every way, but it’s impossible to live up to that _____.",
        "answer": "ideal"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you do a little research on the price of a new car, you can make an _____ decision on how much you should pay.",
        "answer": "informed"
    },
    {
        "question": "After the global _____ finished, many countries changed the way that they created medicines.",
        "answer": "pandemic"
    },
    {
        "question": "Your drink would be healthier for you if you _____ the amount of sugar you add to it.",
        "answer": "reduce"
    },
    {
        "question": "You recent study habits _____ that you are taking this course very seriously.",
        "answer": "indicate"
    },
    {
        "question": "Our teacher taught us that diamonds are actually _____ crystals.",
        "answer": "carbon"
    },
    {
        "question": "This type of butterfly lives in a forest _____.",
        "answer": "habitat"
    },
    {
        "question": "Congratulations! Getting a perfect score on your driver’s test is quite an _____.",
        "answer": "achievement"
    },
    {
        "question": "Red skies at sunset often _____ an approaching typhoon.",
        "answer": "indicate"
    },
    {
        "question": "Many animals are losing _____ due to human activity.",
        "answer": "habitat"
    },
    {
        "question": "We can make ourselves happier once we have the _____ of what we really want in our lives.",
        "answer": "consciousness"
    }
]